Look at all these people, Kate.
Do you think there's a festival?
Come on, Connie. Let's go home.
But—
Kate?
Kate! Where are you?!
Wow...
She's so pretty.
A curse on you.
A curse upon you all!
Y-You fiend!
Fiend!
Murderess!
Hear, hear!
You're the cursed one!
It's over! She's dead!
Dead and gone!
Serves her right!
LESSER PALACE (GRAND MERILLIAN)
It's been ten years since that night
in Saint Mark's Square,
and I, Constance Grail, am now sixteen.
Allow me to congratulate you, Miss Grail.
Thank you very much, Viscount Hamsworth.
Surely the Fates will bless your union,
what with the Grail family motto
of "Be you sincere."
"Be you sincere," huh?
This all started a few months ago.
My father, the living embodiment
of the Grail family's sincerity,
found himself under a mountain of debt.
I'm sorry, Connie.
On the condition that
the Bronson Company pay it,
I became engaged to
Mr. Bronson's son and heir, Neil.
Neil Bronson, at your service.
I can't deny that I'd dreamed
of marrying for love.
But a plain, dull girl like me,
getting a handsome, well-mannered gentleman
to consent to become her husband?
I should consider myself blessed...
Or so I thought.
I heard the news, Connie!
You're engaged to Neil Bronson,
but everyone is talking
about him and Pamela Francis!
Pamela Francis?
Yes! Someone saw them in each other's arms
when they thought no one was watching!
It seems Neil simply worships her.
Don't you think, Kate?
Really, Mylene, you should stop
spreading groundless rumors.
No one would act that way after
just getting engaged, and you know it.
I wouldn't be so sure.
I hear Pamela goes through men the way
the rest of us go through dance partners.
Really, there is such a thing
as delicacy, you know?
I trust Neil.
He was his usual kind self
to me this very day.
Neil and... Pamela?!
Oh...
I wish I could pretend I hadn't seen them.
Given the circumstances of our engagement,
I knew I couldn't expect love.
But even so, I must face him with sincerity.
We need to talk things out.
What a beautiful lady.
Um... My name is Constance Grail.
I hate to pry, but are you feeling all right?
What fun it looks.
Won't you come inside?
May I?
What? But of course.
I'm in!
You have my gratitude, girl.
"G-Girl"?
What should I say to Neil?
Um...
C-Congratulations on your engagement.
Thank you very much.
If I remember correctly,
I often see her with Pamela.
Brenda, your hairpin is falling out.
Perhaps you should just take it off.
Y-Yes, I think I will.
There. That's better.
I left my purse on the second floor.
Would you hold on to my hairpin for me
while I go and fetch it?
Yes, of course. Think nothing of it.
Brenda's been gone a long time...
Constance Grail!
You've behaved outrageously.
Pamela? Neil?
I know that your family is in dire straits,
but don't you think
you've taken this too far?
To be frank, I question your character.
Wh-Whatever do you mean?
My. You expect us to believe you ignorant?
That simply won't do.
I know that you stole Brenda's hairpin.
I heard the whole story.
No sooner had you fixed her hair
than she realized her priceless pin was missing.
Tell me, Constance Grail,
what do you say to that?
What do you mean?
I'm sure someone in need of coin
would have done anything for it.
Yes, I'm painfully aware of how you must feel.
I know all about your family's
lamentable situation.
B-But Brenda asked me to...
Then show us your purse.
If you're no thief,
that shouldn't pose a problem.
Constance, you didn't...
No!
Oh, dear me.
And what do we have here?
I would implore you for an explanation.
So she did steal it?
A Grail, of all people?
Brenda asked me to hold on to it.
She asked you to hold on to this?
Even though you barely know each other?
I find that hard to believe.
Brenda!
Please, tell them!
You asked me, remember?!
You asked me to hold on to it
while you got your purse!
You remember, don't you?
Why won't you tell them, Brenda?
Brenda, please!
Your excuses are growing disgraceful.
Look, poor Brenda is frightened.
It's all right, Brenda.
You needn't say a thing.
There you have it, Neil.
You see what Constance is like.
You ought to object
to your engagement at once.
She's committed a crime.
People will lose confidence in
the Bronson Company if you marry her.
But there's no proof that she stole it.
Proof?
Why, everyone here is a witness!
I know. Viscount Hamsworth
is a man of the cloth.
You could lodge your objection with him now.
You're wrong! I would never steal!
"Be you sincere"?
So much for the Grail family's sincerity.
You're nothing but a common thief.
You're wrong...
No...
Someone, anyone, help me!
Help!
Very well.
I'll help you.
Who's that?
But in exchange...
A thief, you say?
I wonder...
Which of us is the real thief?
Constance Grail...
She makes such a show
of her ridiculous "sincerity."
I've never been able to stomach her.
Yet she gets engaged to the Neil Bronson?
Why should she get special treatment
when her looks and her family's wealth
can't hold a candle to mine?!
That's why I decided to use Brenda
to crush her! So how...
Me, a thief? Whatever do you mean?
I won't stand for such slanderous—
Well, were you aware...
that I am engaged to the man you were
so shamelessly rutting with in the shrubbery?
I... I did no such thing!
Neil and I kissed, nothing more!
Pamela!
They kissed?
The rumors are true, then.
Oh dear. It seems I misspoke.
You were only kissing...
another woman's fiancé.
But surely you can see the thievery.
That still doesn't change the fact
that you stole Brenda's hairpin!
Very well.
Say, you there.
Give me a moment. Let me search my memory.
Ah, yes. Wayne.
Wayne Hastings.
You saw us, did you not?
I... I don't...
If you'd rather not speak up, so be it.
But tread carefully.
Many others know the truth as well as you do.
As it happens, I have an excellent memory.
Viscountess Stan,
Miss Bower,
and Knight Pelham were all there.
Additionally...
you there in the lemon dress,
although it seems she does not know your name.
All four of you were looking at us
at the time, were you not?
Never mind, ladies and gentlemen.
You don't have to say a word.
However, as I detest awkward ambiguities,
I will ask you once more.
Wayne Hastings! Stop staring
at your shoes and look at me.
That's better.
Now, Wayne, give me
the benefit of your opinion.
Is it right to frame an innocent person
for a crime they did not commit?
What of those who know the truth
but choose to remain silent for their own sakes?
I'll tell you what I think.
Anyone who does such a thing will go to hell,
and those who turn a blind eye
are equally guilty.
Now, Wayne, I'd like you to imagine something.
Should the truth ever come to light,
where would that leave you,
and what will people say about you?
Look at me.
I won't allow you to take your eyes off me.
I... I saw.
I saw it. Miss Grail didn't steal anything.
All she did was neaten Brenda's hair.
And Brenda asked her to hold on to that hairpin!
I... I heard that as well!
I also saw them.
As did I.
It happened just as she said!
Is this true, Pamela?
Neil! N-No!
I mean, Brenda—
Oh, of course!
Brenda lied to me!
Look, poor Brenda is frightened.
It's all right, Brenda.
You needn't say a thing.
My.
What is all this fuss about?
Oh, it's the nouveau riche hog. Lovely.
My lord, as it happens...
Ah, I see.
You've had an unfortunate evening, Miss Grail.
Yes, dreadful.
I wish to turn to the goddesses
in the face of such mistreatment.
Might I trouble you to assist me?
In objecting to your engagement, you mean?
Will it be accepted?
Not at once, I fear, since your engagement
has already been made public.
The other party has a right to speak,
so an appropriate venue would—
That is none of my concern.
Spare me your quibbles
and annul my engagement,
you dithering fool.
Otherwise...
the world will know that Dominic Hamsworth
hosted a party tonight at the Grand Merillian
where couples conducted themselves
scandalously in the exalted royal gardens.
And I will personally stop at nothing
to ensure that His Royal Majesty hears of it.
Who is this woman?
She's nothing like the Constance Grail I know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I sincerely apologize for casting
a pall over this splendid occasion.
I hope you will bless this young couple
burning with illicit love.
Now, if you will all excuse me...
Please, wait a moment!
I gave my best wishes
to Miss Grail, you know.
So I found your antics somewhat vexing.
Did you know?
Where I come from, thieves are
made to wear burning-hot shoes...
and dance until they die.
Ah, it's begun.
The first in ten years.
I wonder how long those children will last.
I must say, Constance gave me quite a shock.
I could almost have believed...
that Scarlett Castiel had returned from hell.
A dream?
It was just a dream!
You're awake at last, Constance Grail.
Wh-Wh-What's going on?
Whatever do you mean?
Are you still half asleep?
Um... Whom do I have
the pleasure of addressing?
I am Scarlett Castiel.
Wait, wait, wait. You must be joking.
Scarlett Castiel was executed ten years ago.
Goodness, girl.
Tell me...
Do I look alive to you?
B-But...
Scarlett Castiel was
the wickedest woman of her age.
She even plotted to poison
Miss Cecilia, her rival in love.
Crown Prince Enrique unmasked her
at the Grand Merillian
and ended their engagement.
But she'd behaved so monstrously
that she was put to death as well.
That's certainly one way to sum it up.
I don't remember a thing
about the day of my execution.
But the Grand Merillian,
where we met yesterday,
is where that brainless Enrique
and scheming Cecilia humiliated me.
Even now, just thinking of it is infuriating.
H-How can you speak of the prince that way?
Or call the crown princess "scheming"?
In any case, the next thing I knew,
I found myself there.
But try as I might, I couldn't enter the hall.
It must have been thanks to you
that I finally managed it.
You were the first person to ever notice me.
You seem plain, dull,
and generally unremarkable,
but you may take pride in the fact
that you can see me, if nothing else!
That feels a tad harsh.
Still, what are you doing in my house?
Why, because I have yet to receive my due.
Your due?
My, have you forgotten?
Surely you didn't think I would help
a perfect stranger for nothing.
Very well.
I'll help you.
But in exchange...
Listen well, Constance Grail.
You will spend the rest of your life
ensuring that I have my revenge.
Your... revenge?